A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia 1915-1925
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia 1915-1925
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.472 V
This collection consists of ca. 4500 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was acquired via an archival transfer from the Office of the President, 1981 January 12.
Biographical/Historical Information
Prior to 1904, the University of Virginia did not have a president, the chief administrative officer was the Chairman of the Faculty.
Scope and Content Information
Correspondence and related papers of President Edwin Anderson Alderman originally kept in the President's office and maintained in a separate file labelled "Personal."
Contents List
- "A" Miscellaneous 1919-1925 (Box 1)
- Arlington Memorial 1920-1922 (Box 1)
- "Ba-Bo" Miscellaneous 1920-1925 (Box 1)
  references to Red Cross
- "Br-Ch" Miscellaneous 1920-1925 (Box 1)
  references to Prohibition
- "Ci-Co" Miscellaneous 1920-1925 (Box 1)
  references to Civic Forum
- "Cr-Cu" Miscellaneous 1920-1925 (Box 1)
- Co-operative Education Association 1921-1925 (Box 1)
- "Da" Miscellaneous 1919-1924 (Box 1)
  references to University Budget
- "De-E" Miscellaneous 1915-1925 (Box 1)
- "F" Miscellaneous 1919-1925 (Box 1)
- Financial Matters 1919-1925 (Box 2)
  (1-6 of 9)
- Financial Matters 1919-1925 (Box 3)
  (7-9 of 9)
- Financial Matters -- Bills List 1919-1924 (Box 3)
- "G" Miscellaneous 1919-1925 (Box 3)
- General Education Board 1919-1925 (Box 3)
  (1-2 of 5)
- General Education Board 1919-1925 (Box 4)
  (3-5 of 5)
- Georgia Chancellorship -- declined 1925 (Box 4)
- Governor -- E. Lee Trinkle 1919-1925 (Box 4)
  references to Student Loans
- "H" Miscellaneous 1919-1925 (Box 4)
  references to Institute of International Relations
- Hall of Fame 1919-1925 (Box 4)
  references to Women's Sufferage (2 folders)
- Houdon Statute Presentation 1921 (Box 5)
- "I" Miscellaneous 1922-1924 (Box 5)
- Institute for Government Research 1922-1925 (Box 5)
- Institute of Economics 1922-1925 (Box 5)
  references to Institute Publications
- Institute of Politics 1922-1924 (Box 5)
- Invitations to Speak 1919-1925 (Box 5)
  (1-5 of 16)
- Invitations to Speak 1919-1925 (Box 6)
  (6-11 of 16)
- Invitations to Speak 1919-1925 (Box 7)
  (12-16 of 16)
- "J-K" Miscellaneous 1920-1925 (Box 7)
  reference to Woodrow Wilson Foundation
- Jefferson Article, by Dr. Alderman for New York Times1925 (Box 7)
- Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation 1923-1925 (Box 8)
- "L" Miscellaneous 1919-1925 (Box 8)
  references to restoration of the University of Louvain
- Library of Southern Literature 1920-1925 (Box 8)
- "M" Miscellaneous 1919-1925 (Box 8)
- "Mc" Miscellaneous 1919-1925 (Box 8)
- Monticello Custodianship 1922-1924 (Box 8)
- "N-O" Miscellaneous 1919-1925 (Box 8)
  references to National Institute of Social Sciences
- Naval Academy 1920-1922 (Box 8)
- "P" Miscellaneous 1919-1925 (Box 8)
- Page, Walter H. 1920-1925 (Box 8)
- "R" Miscellaneous 1919-1925 (Box 9)
- "S" Miscellaneous 1919-1925 (Box 9)
  references to George Washington's Home
- Saranac Library 1922-1923 (Box 9)
- Teacher's Preventorium 1923 (Box 9)
- "T-V" Miscellaneous 1919-1925 (Box 9)
- "W-Z" Miscellaneous 1919-1925 (Box 9)
  references to Westmoreland Club
- Woodrow Wilson Foundation 1921-1925 (Box 9)